<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Spells</name>
        <description>The Homebrew Spells from D&amp;D Wiki</description>
        <author url="https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Begone_Thot,_Variant_(5e_Spell)">April Fool's Page</author>
        <update version="0.1">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://github.com/LePorpoise/Aurora-Builder/blob/Spells/spells/homebrew/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

<element name="Begone Thot" type="Spell" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_SPELL_BEGONE_THOT_VARIANT">
        <supports>Wizard, Sorcerer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A pure white magic circle surrounds you spreading out in a 30-foot-radius as dark clouds manifest in the sky above you and wind, rain and lightning come down. You hold your hand up high and in a deep booming voice that sends shockwaves to all within the range, you denounce the thot you've targeted. In that moment you let out a deafening cry, "BEGONE THOT!" The creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw, or take 2d8 psychic damage and be pushed 15 feet directly away from you.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels. </i></b>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each spell slot level above 1st. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level instead of being knocked back the creature comes under the turned effect. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level instead of being knocked back or turned the creature is instead banished. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level instead of being knocked back, turned, or banished the creature takes an additional 10d8 psychic damage. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 9th level instead of being knocked back, turned, or banished or that target taking an addition 10d8 psychic damage, all creature within range that are thots take an additional 7d8 psychic damage, if this would reduce any of the damaged creatures to 0 hit points their souls are destroyed. </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">lightning</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
</element>
</elements>