<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Spells</name>
        <description>The Homebrew Spells from D&amp;D Wiki</description>
        <author url="https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Begone_Thot,_Variant_(5e_Spell)">April Fool's Page</author>
        <update version="0.1">
            <file name="spells.xml" url="https://github.com/LePorpoise/Aurora-Builder/blob/Spells/spells/homebrew/spells.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Virtuous Fire" type="Cantrip" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_CLASS_FEATURE_DRAGONHUNTER_VIRTUOUS_FIRE">
        <supports>Dragonhunter</supports>
        <description>
            <p> Class : Dragonhunter</p>
            <p> Starting at 1st level, you have unlocked virtues so pure that you can create blue flame at will.</p>
            <p class="indent"> You can cast Produce Flame at will. Charisma becomes your spellcasting modifier. Your spell save becomes 8 + Proficiency + Charisma.</p>
            <p class="indent"> A flickering flame appears in your hand. The flame remains there for the duration and harms neither you nor your equipment. The flame sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. The spell ends if you dismiss it as an action or if you cast it again. You can also attack with the flame, although doing so ends the spell. When you cast this spell, or as an action on a later turn, you can hurl the flame at a creature within 30 feet of you.</p>
            <p> Make a ranged spell attack. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 fire damage. This spell’s damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8),  11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">fire</set>
            <set name="level">0</set>
            <set name="school">Conjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
            <set name="range">self</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Begone Thot" type="Spell" source="D&amp;D Wiki" id="ID_WIKI_SPELL_BEGONE_THOT_VARIANT">
        <supports>Wizard, Sorcerer</supports>
        <description>
            <p>A pure white magic circle surrounds you spreading out in a 30-foot-radius as dark clouds manifest in the sky above you and wind, rain and lightning come down. You hold your hand up high and in a deep booming voice that sends shockwaves to all within the range, you denounce the thot you've targeted. In that moment you let out a deafening cry, "BEGONE THOT!" The creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw, or take 2d8 psychic damage and be pushed 15 feet directly away from you.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels. </i></b>When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each spell slot level above 1st. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level instead of being knocked back the creature comes under the turned effect. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level instead of being knocked back or turned the creature is instead banished. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 7th level instead of being knocked back, turned, or banished the creature takes an additional 10d8 psychic damage. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 9th level instead of being knocked back, turned, or banished or that target taking an addition 10d8 psychic damage, all creature within range that are thots take an additional 7d8 psychic damage, if this would reduce any of the damaged creatures to 0 hit points their souls are destroyed. </p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="keywords">lightning</set>
            <set name="level">1</set>
            <set name="school">Abjuration</set>
            <set name="time">1 action</set>
            <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
            <set name="range">30 feet</set>
            <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
            <set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
            <set name="materialComponent"></set>
            <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
            <set name="isRitual">false</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>